# IVAN SERGIIENKO

## Brief Summary

I want to switch from Frontend to Python (ideally to machine learning). I've recently completed an ML course, where I used Python: https://certificate.ithillel.ua/view/28203443

I feel passionate about innovation, AI, robots, IoT, big data, etc.

I've got 7 years of experience in web development, mostly frontend. Also I've got some experience with backend (php, Java) and DevOps. 4 years I worked for a big UK tech company (as a remote contractor).

I love Vim, Linux, git, clean code, top-down design, TDD, SOLID, KISS. People say I have good communication skills and attention to details. I challenge decisions and status quo when I see a good reason to do so.

#### EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

- 6 years of Frontend
- 1 year of PHP
- A bit of Bash, Linux, AWS, GitlabCI, Docker, Java, NodeJS
- Python used in the ML course (Numpy, Pandas, SciKit, NLTK, PyTorch, Google Colab, MobileNetV2, MNasNet)

# My Articles

Synthesizing sound with JavaScript-sine wave: https://medium.com/@darthvanger/synthesize-sound-with-javascript-sine-wave-940f9cd7dae2

## My projects

- NeuralNotes a notes keeping app: https://github.com/DarthVanger/NeuralNotes
- JS Guitar synthesizer (zero dependencies): https://github.com/DarthVanger/guitar-synth-js
- FFmpeg cut and merge (bash): https://github.com/DarthVanger/ffmpeg-cut-and-merge

My StackOverflow reputation - 843 (Ubuntu 341, Vim 301, Super User 131)

- My profile: https://stackexchange.com/users/1823670/darthvanger?tab=accounts
- ML answer (4 upvotes): https://stackoverflow.com/a/70230342/1657101
- Python answer: https://stackoverflow.com/a/70552540/1657101

#### My (small) opensource contributions

- Sourcemap-codec bug fix: https://github.com/Rich-Harris/sourcemap-codec/pull/76
- Terraform Newrelic provider docs: https://github.com/newrelic/terraform-provider-newrelic/pull/546
- Victory Charts docs: https://github.com/FormidableLabs/victory-docs/pull/

# EXPERIENCE IN DETAIL

Mar 2021 - present: freelance, pet projects, courses, chillinng:)

Mar 2020 - Feb 2021: One of the biggest UK online grocery retailers. Web UI for supply chain management

Working with frontend and backend, participating in technical discoveries for upcoming features, code reviews, security code reviews.

- React, Redux, TypeScript, Jest, Enzyme 100% unit test coverage
- Java, Spring, Spring Boot, GitlabCI, Terraform, Kibana, NewRelic

2018 - Mar 2020: One of the biggest UK online grocery retailers. React UI library  $\,$ 

Developing a library of UI components with documentation, tutorials and tests. Gathering and building requirements, working closely with the UX design team.

- React, Bootstrap 4, TypeScript, SCSS
- Lerna, Jest, Enzyme, GitlabCI, semantic-release

2016-2018. One of the biggest UK online grocery retailers. Vehicles fleet management system

Working on frontend of a big app (60 screens, 20k lines of Angular v1.x).

- Data tables (filter, pagination, sort), CRUD.
- i18n; SSO; user roles; feature flags.
- e2e Selenium tests (protractor + jasmine).
- e2e REST API tests (chai-http, mocha, superagent)
- Deploying Selenium grid on Docker using Ansible
- AWS Elastic Beanstalk, S3; GoCD, Kibana, New Relic.

2015: DataArt. Vacancies & Candidates management system

Working on UI (Backbone + Marionette + RequireJS).

2014-2015: ISD Group. Social network for moms

Working with PHP and JS for a social network.

- require.js, gulp, nodeJS
- php, mysql, redis
- Developed an algorithm to suggest related posts based on user activity

2010 Summer: Server at Moody Gardens - Galveston Island, Texas, USA

### **EDUCATION**

Kyiv Polytechnic Institute: 3 years of Applied physics (Institute of physics and technology) + 3 years of printing and publishing.

#### Courses:

- Machine learning (Hillel IT school)
- Algorithms basics (Projector school)
- Programming methodology Standford cs106a (Youtube)
- Internet History, Technology, and Security University of Michigan (Coursera)
- Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies Princeton University (Coursera)
- Java web development (Epam school)

## LANGUAGES

English - Upper Intermediate (around 8/10, both spoken and written). I've been working for 2 years with UK teams remotely, speaking English every day.

## Contact

tel. +380930780138 (telegram preferable)

email: darthvanger@gmail.com

linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivan-sergiienko-76494b73

# Personal Info

Age: 31 years

Residence: Yaremche, Ukraine